[
    {
        "question": "............... fishing is not developed in Brazil.",
        "options": [
            "Inland",
            "Open sea",
            "Marine"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Providing boarding and lodging fall under …………… activity.",
        "options": [
            "Tertiary",
            "Primary"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "In which sector Brazil has not invested in India?",
        "options": [
            "Mining",
            "IT",
            "Biofuels",
            "Auto sector"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the occupation which gives boost to economic development of a country",
        "options": [
            "Agriculture",
            "Tertiary",
            "Forestry"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The per capita income of India is high",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Khadi Industry requires ……………. raw material.",
        "options": [
            "Cotton",
            "Jute",
            "Silk"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the 2 main crops of Brazil.",
        "options": [
            "Rice – Maize",
            "Coffee-tobacco",
            "Soyabean-rice"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Gujarat and Rajasthan produce bulk of ............... in the country",
        "options": [
            "Salt",
            "Spices",
            "Pickles"
        ],
        "answer":1
    },
    {
        "question": "Excellent fishing ground is available in ............... Atlantic ocean",
        "options": [
            "North",
            "Eastern",
            "South"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "dentify the correct group.The states with most of the reserves of metallic minerals",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat - Rajasthan - Tamil Nadu",
            "Jharkhand - Orissa - Madhya Pradesh",
            "Rajasthan - Maharashtra - Punjab"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Cuddapah stones are found in ...............",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Andhra Pradesh",
            "Himachal Pradesh"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the following group of fruits.Bananas, pineapples, oranges, citrus fruits",
        "options": [
            "Tropical",
            "Temperature",
            "Mediterranean"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Extraction of sugar cane juice is ............... activity.",
        "options": [
            "Secondary",
            "Primary",
            "Tertiary"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Fishing is carried out in Brazil with ............... techniques.",
        "options": [
            "Primitive",
            "Modern",
            "Traditional"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "............... fishing is carried out in rivers, canals irrigation channels Tanks and ponds.",
        "options": [
            "Open-sea",
            "Inland",
            "Marine"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Fish terms an important part of the diet people living in ............... Areas",
        "options": [
            "Coastal",
            "Centra",
            "Plateau"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Along with fertile soil with other factor is important for agriculture",
        "options": [
            "Water",
            "Seeds",
            "Climate"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct group:The refineries situated close to petroleum producing areas",
        "options": [
            "Koyali - Digboi - Noonmati",
            "Mathura - Barauni - Digboi",
            "Koyali - Barauni - Mathura"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the continent whose countries are not the member of BRICS.",
        "options": [
            "South America",
            "North America",
            "Asia",
            "Africa"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "In ............... Economy public and private sectors co-exists",
        "options": [
            "Mixed",
            "Capital",
            "Socialist"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    }
]